# **Morgane Fortin**

#### Data scientist

33 years, French citizen

🗥 Dublin, Ireland

ganetin@gmail.com

+33 6 70 59 82 21

ganetin.github.io

github.com/ganetin

### Technical Skills —

Linux
Python
Fortran
Mathematica
C/C++
Git
HTML and CSS

## Soft Skills -

Independent thinker

Responsible & determined

Excellent communicator

🏖 Team builder & project initiator

Well-organized and disciplined

# Languages -

French
English
Polish
Italian
German

## Personal interests

Sailing for 20+ years

Cinema, literature, opera

Video games

Genealogy

Amateur crypto investor

First aid diploma

#### **Personal Statement**

Former astrophysicist turned data scientist bringing 11 years of analytical research experience and dynamism to an organization seeking innovative data-oriented solutions. My adaptability and strong motivation allow me to quickly learn new skills and tools, both in a team and independently. My solid background in problem-solving, programming, and data visualisation, together with my ability to communicate complex ideas across diverse audiences in uncomplicated terms, will be an asset to any organisation.

#### Education

Mar. 2019	Data Science School in (Astro-)Particle Physics and Cosmology Probability, Statistics and Machine Learning
2012	<b>PhD in Astronomy and Astrophysics</b> Warsaw (PL) & Paris (FR) Polish Academy of Sciences & Paris Observatory with highest honors; joint Polish & French Ph.D. programme
2009	MSc in Astrophysics  Paris (FR)  Pierre and Marie Curie University, Ecole Normale  Supérieure & Paris Observatory – with honors

### **Work Experience**

Aug. – Sept. 2020 Data Scientist - S2DS Fellow

Successfully delivered team project for SEGRO PLC (Europe's largest investor in industrial Real Estate) to optimise client's portfolio through Manipulation & Visualization of Geospatial Data (GeoPandas, Folium, Shapely), Web-scraping, Geocoding and extensive use of

APIs.

2014 – Sept. 2020 Assistant Professor (Nuclear Astrophysics) Warsaw (PL)

Extensive use of Python (NumPy, Matplotlib, SciPy, ...), Data Visualisation and Machine-Learning techniques (linear regression, confidence intervals, correlations, calibration and optimisation of multi-parameter models) on a cluster

Published 30+ articles in renowned international journals, gave 5+ invited talks, 20+ seminars/presentations around the world, and lectures in Physics at all levels across Europe.

Key contributor to winning grants ( $\in$ 1.2M in total).

Conceived and organised 3 international conferences (50-250 participants each).

Member of 3 European networks & 3 Space Mission projects.

Contributed to popularisation of astronomy (books, movies, interviews, translations).

Mentored female students in STEM from around the world.

#### 2016 – Sept. 2020 Visiting Researcher

Coimbra (PT)

Completed 10+ projects including machine-learning aspects, acting as a bridge between Astrophysics and Nuclear Physics.

2012 – 2014 Postdoctoral Researcher

Rome (IT)

Worked as an independent researcher building contacts around the world.

Expanded my expertise from Astrophysics to include Nuclear Physics.